Guide to the Gould family papers, 1799-[ca. 1869]
Gould family papers, 1799-[ca. 1869]
- Series IV. Other Writings: journals, volumes, lecture notes, sermons
  - Volume, n.d. (Box 11)
    "Recipe to prevent infection from the typhus fever"
  - Lecture notes, post 1848 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    John Stanton Gould geography lectures: 1 "The effects of land and water," 2-4 physical geography, 5-9 climatology, 10 vegetation and demography
  - Sermons, 1825, 1854 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Rev. William R. Bogardus (father-in-law of J. Romeyn Berry), 1825, April and November 1854
  - Sermon, 1848 (Box 12)
    "They are not of the world even as I am not of the world," first sermon written by J. R. B. (J. Romeyn Berry), Chapel Jany.13, 1841; 2 D. Lech. R. N.B - Dec - 1849; Bergen St., Feb. 1850; Pres. L. R. N. B - Mar. 14, 1850; Jersey City, Mar 24, 1860; Milltown, June 1850; Pollifly Sch. House, Aug. 1850; Bergen Sch. House, Oct. 1850; Bedminster, June 23, 1850; Pleimant, Oct. 27, 1850; Syracuse, Oct. 3, 1852; Syracuse Lect, Oct. 11, 1854
  - Sermon, 1861 (Box 12)
    "Christian Patriotism," Reformed Dutch Church of Kinderhook, June 23rd, 1861 (printed)
  - Sermon, 1862 (Box 12)
    "The Call of Peter," Coxsackie Nov. 30, 1862; K. Jan 25, 1863; J. C. Nov. 6, 1864; M. Feb. 26, 1871; M. Feb. 1, 1880 (1 & 2 pts); M. Feb. 8, 1880 (3 & 4 pts)
  - Sermon, 1862 (Box 12)
    "Recognition of Saints in Heaven," Kinderhook, 1862
  - Sermon, 1864 (Box 12)
    "God's Voice of Encouragement to the Nation," Jersey City, August 4th, 1864 (printed)
  - Sermon, 1870 (Box 12)
    "The joy of Angels over a sinner's repentance," M. Aug. 14, 1870; M. Aug. 3, 1873; M. Dec. 16, 1877; Cliffside Sep. 21, 1879; M. Dec. 10, 1882; R. Apr. 8, 1888
  - Sermon, 1870 (Box 12)
    "Paul before Festus," M. Oct. 10, 1870; M. Apr. 1876; M. July 13, 1884
  - Sermon, 1870 (Box 12)
    "He came unto His own & His own rec'd Him not," M. Christmas 1870, 1878
  - Sermon, 1871 (Box 12)
    "Total Abstinance," M. Oct. 29, 1871; M. July 18, 1875; R. June 2, 1889
  - Sermon, 1871 (Box 12)
    "The great Supper," M. Nov. 1871; Central P. C. Newark - 1872; M. Extemp - Mar. 29, 1874; R. Apr. 20, 1880
  - Sermon, 1871 (Box 12)
    "Sermon to the Young," M. Dec. 10, 1871; M. Oct. 1885
  - Sermon, 1872 (Box 12)
    "The Nativity," M. December 22, 1872
  - Sermon, 1873 (Box 12)
    "The one thing needful," M. Sept. 28, 1873; M. Jan. 27, 1878
  - Sermon, 1876 (Box 12)
    "The abundance of pardon," M. Feby 6, 1876; M. Aug. 6, 1882; R. Mar. 16, 1890
  - Sermon, 1876 (Box 12)
    "Parable of the two sons," M. Mar. 1876; R. Extemp - May 31, 1891
  - Sermon, 1876 (Box 12)
    Easter sermon, M. April 16, 1876; R. Apr. 20, 1889
  - Sermon, 1876 (Box 12)
    "A sermon to young men," M. Nov. 12, 1876; M. Dec. 9, 1883
  - Sermon, 1877 (Box 12)
    "Memory," M. Jan. 28, 1877; M. Mar. 24, 1878; R. Sept. 1, 1889
  - Sermon, 1877 (Box 12)
    "The good fight of faith," M. Nov. 11, 1877; Calowill Nov. 18, 1877; M. Oct. 26, 1884
  - Sermon, 1878 (Box 12)
    "As thy days, so shall they strength be," M. March 1878; Newark Chist Av. R. C. Nov. 3, 1878 ["Except under very special circumstances, I do not want this manuscript put into the hands of any but my own kin. W. B. Berry]
  - Sermon, 1878 (Box 12)
    "Total abstinance in its relations to the home," M. May 12, 1878
  - Sermon, 1878 (Box 12)
    "The great supper," M. Oct. 13, 1878
  - Sermon, 1878 (Box 12)
    "Sober mindedness - a sermon to young men," M. Nov. 10, 1878
  - Sermon, 1879 (Box 12)
    "The typical young professor," M. Jan. 26, 1879
  - Sermon, 1879 (Box 12)
    The nature and reward of fidelity," M. Feb. 23, 1879; Orange Central C. Apr. 20, 1879; Newark North Ch. June 29, 1879; M. Aug. 24, 1884 (first part only); M. Aug. 31, 1884 (second part); R. Nov. 18, 1888
  - Sermon, 1879 (Box 12)
    "Yet there is room," M. Mar 2, 1879; M. Mar. 22, 1885
  - Sermon, 1880 (Box 12)
    "God with his people - a New Year sermon," M. Jan. 4, 1880
  - Sermon, 1881 (Box 12)
    "The Word of Life so Near," 2 printed copies, Montclair, N. J., July 10th, 1881
  - Sermon, 1881 (Box 12)
    "Silence amid Mystery," one mss. copy, one printed copy, Montclair, N. J., Sept. 25, 1881
  - Sermon, 1881 (Box 12)
    "If the dead rise not, let us eat and drink for tomorrow.. .," M. Nov. 6, 1881,S. Park Ch., Newark Mar. 20, 1884
  - Sermon, 1881 (Box 12)
    "The Word of Life so Near," Montclair, N. J., July 10, 1881
  - Sermon, 1882 (Box 12)
    "The Believer's Christ-Life," M. Jan. 1, 1882; M. Jan. 24, 1882, Cong. Ch. Extemp
  - Sermon, 1882 (Box 12)
    "The Coming of X. the great Expectation of the world," M. Dec. 24, 1882; R. Dec. 23, 1888
  - Sermon, 1883 (Box 12)
    "The Past," M. Dec. 30, 1883; R. Dec. 29, 1889
  - Sermon, 1884 (Box 12)
    "All things are lawful.. .," M. Mar. 16, 1884
  - Sermon, 1884 (Box 12)
    "The importance of Christ's Resurrection," M. Easter, April 13, 1884
  - Sermon, 1884 (Box 12)
    "Weakness & strength with particular reference to the matter of total abstinence," M. April 20, 1884
  - Sermon, 1884 (Box 12)
    "The results of Paul's ministry in Athens," M. May 18, 1884; Hudson P.C. Aug. 14, 1887; R. Dec. 21, 1890
  - Sermon, 1884 (Box 12)
    "Love of God & Love to God," Montclair Dec. 28, 1884
  - Sermon, 1885 (Box 13)
    "If any man be in X. L. he is a new creature.. .," M. Jan. 4, 1885
  - Sermon, 1885 (Box 13)
    "Therefore we ought to give the more earnest heed to the.. .," M. Jan. 18, 1885
  - Sermon, 1885 (Box 13)
    "The beloved disciple's vision of his Lord," M. Apr. 5, 1885
  - Sermon, 1886 (Box 13)
    "Lost Opportunities," M. Mar. 28, 1886
  - Sermon, 1886 (Box 13)
    "The Evidence of X's Resurrection," M. Apr. 25, 1886
  - Sermon, 1886 (Box 13)
    "Jesus and the Sorrow in Bethany," M. July 18,1886
  - Sermon, 1886 (Box 13)
    "The Personality and Rule of X's Discipleship," M. Aug. 15, 1886
  - Sermon, 1886 (Box 13)
    "Simeon with Jesus in his arms The Attitude and Outlook of Faith A Sermon for the aged," M. Dec. 26, 1886
  - Sermon, 1887 (Box 13)
    "Christ inviting the Lord's request," M. Jan. 2, 1887
  - Sermon, 1887 (Box 13)
    "The scope of mercy," M. Jan. 10, 1887
  - Sermon, 1887 (Box 13)
    "The Resurrection of the body pledged & typified in X's resurrection," M. April 10, 1887
  - Sermon, 1888 (Box 13)
    "Now is our salvation nearer than when we believe of.. .," R. Jan. 1, 1888
  - Sermon, 1888 (Box 13)
    "The Unfinished Tower & its Foolish Builder," R. Feb. 12, 1888
  - Sermon, 1888 (Box 13)
    "Christ's Eternal Throne in its relations to His Church," Montclair, May 10, 1888
  - Sermon, 1890 (Box 13)
    "Charge to Congregation," Po'keepsie, Nov. 10, 1890
  - Sermon, 1890 (Box 13)
    "The visit of the Wise Men to Bethlehem," R. Dec. 28, 1890
  - Sermon, 1891 (Box 13)
    "All sufficient Grace," R. Jan. 4, 1891
  - Sermon (Box 13)
    "The Power of God in X's Resurrection - the Measure of His power towards us," M. Mar. 25, (no year)
  - Reprint of Article, 1890 (Box 13)
    "Church Discipline," from The Presbyterian and Reformed Review, April 1890
  - Reprint of Article (Box 13)
    "The Vows of Scripture," July 1867
  - Volume, 1885 (Box 13)
    The Gospel according to St. Luke
  - Religious certifications of Rev. William Bogardus and of Rev. J. Romeyn Berry. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Certificate making J. Romeyn Berry a pastor was signed by Romeyn Berry [what relation is he to J. Romeyn Berry?]
  - Newspaper Clippings of the Rev. J. Romeyn Berry, b. 1827, d. 6/5/1891 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Rev. Berry, was pastor of a number of churches, (Dr. William Bogardus Berry's father, spouse of Elizabeth Wright Gould), clippings include J. Romeyn Berry's obituary; J. Romeyn Berry's first wife [name?] was the daughter of a minister named Rev. William Bogardus (b. 1789 d. 1862). She died as a result of an accident 8/1/1869. J. Romeyn Berry's second wife was Harriet V. Berry, mother of Charlotte Berry
  - Rev. J. Romeyn Berry, Miscellany (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Misc. mss. writings -- Poems, scriptures, prose, etc.
  - Two Volumes, 1816, 1828 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    "Receipts - Stephen Gould 5 mo. 1816," book of medicinal remedies and recipes, assorted household hints; "Stephen Gould's Book 4 mo. 15th 1828, begins with medicinal remedy for worms in children
  - Writings, 1890-1892 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Sanford Stoddard's grammar compositions, 1890-1891
  - Printed Materials, 1874-1927 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Bookplates; poetry; graduation program; materials from Connecticut Research Association, Bureau of Mental Health; list of subscribers to The United War Fund; The Town of Stockport, Items Collected For The Daughters of Columbia County Historical Society; Mental Hygiene News, "School of Politics, Conducted by the Greenwich Progressive Club"; Elizabeth A. Drew lectures brochure; brochures re Conference on Modern Parenthood and Child Study Groups, Child Study Association of America, Inc.
  - Printed Materials, 1924-1925 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Materials re Bridgeport Society for Mental Hygiene, 1924-1925
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1888-1911 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Statement re Johnson Bevoni coal yard, Oct. 1888; inventory - S. S. library, 1911; "The Child in Relation to the State,"November 1916; household inventory, June 2nd, 1904; list of names and household items; menu; extract from S. S. Record of Canaan, N.Y., Apr. 13, 18??; card from Mrs. Goodwin Stoddard; card from Cockcroft Silk Co., Inc.; College Club of Bridgeport, constitution; card from "Allan" line and "State" line of steamers, July 13, 1899; report from scholarship committee; genealogical chart; card from Fairfield Garden Club; "How Her Kindergarten Training Helped One Mother"
  - Clippings, 1914-1938 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Miscellaneous clippings
  - Miscellany, 1804, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Confederate notes (4); fractional currency (10 cents), 1864; label from coffee or tea container; silhouettes: Grandfather Wright, Stephen Gould, Isaac Austin, 1804
  - Sketches (Box 14, Folder 8)
    26 original sketches by Hendrik Willem van Loon, #1-4, 6-27
  - Writings, 1940-1943 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Romeyn Berry newspaper columns
  - Genealogy, 1777-1826 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Notice of death of child, 1777; Gould Family genealogical chart, 1794, small book of names of "Newport children (Thomas Thompson's)," 1826
  - Genealogy, 1840 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Book, compiled by Nathan Hammett Gould for his aunt Hannah Rodman Gould, wife of Stephen W. Gould; Nathan was the 4th child of Isaac Gould (2nd child of James and Hannah Wanton Gould); Stephen and Isaac were brothers; Hannah Rodman Gould "dropped the R. and added Jr. to her name"
  - Family Reunion, 1859 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Typescript and photocopies of a pamphlet "Reunion of the Sons & Daughters of Newport, R. I., Aug. 23, 1859
- Series V. Legal Documents
  - Manuscript and Printed Items, 1709-1792 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Will of Charles Dyre, May 9, 1709; Inventory of Daniel Gould estate, April 6, 1716; Account of the people of Rhode Island, "Whites & Blacks & Arms & Ammunition, 1756; Account of the price of silver, 1700-1764; Letter from Charles Browler expressing alarm that a recent Governor's pamphlet encouraged people of New England to rebellion & disloyalty and to "Stir up Sedition in the Colonies," Dec. 15, 1764; "The trial of Dr. William Dodd," an account of his being sentenced to death; Articles of the United Fire Club, Feb. 6, 1783; Supplement to the Newport Mercury, May 29, 1784, Incorporation Act of the City of Newport; Declaration that John Townsend was appointed to Justice of the Peace, May 7, 1792; "Spirit of the Martyrs," book about religious persecution
  - Legal Documents, 1811-1824 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Last will and testament of Stephen Gould (seals and ribbon are in place), probated Dec. 3, 1838; Asa Brooks estate papers, 1816, 1818
  - Legal Documents (continued), 1811-1824 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Martha Stanton's revocation of snuff - witnessed by John Stanton Gould, mentions that she is the wife of John Stanton and dau. of Stephen and Mary Wanton, Feb. 4, 1824
  - Legal Documents, 1854-1879 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Power of attorney from J. S. G. to H. W. G re stock in New York Central Rail Road, American Exchange Bank of City of New York, Rail Road bonds of Hudson River Rail Road, Farmers Bank of Hudson, Feb. 4, 1858; Power of attorney from John Stanton Gould to Hannah W. Gould re stock in Hudson Rail Road and Farmers Bank of Hudson, June 3, 1854; Note to cashier of Commercial Bank of Troy to pay dividend on her stock to John S. Gould, April 26, 1859; John S. Gould deeds the household goods to his wife, Dec. 4, 1864; Statement of personal property of the estate of John Stanton Gould, Nov. 1, 1874 and statement of personal property of Hannah W. Gould, Nov. 1, 1874, another statement dated April 1, 1879
  - Legal Documents, Hannah Wright Gould, 1886-1913 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Account records of Hannah W. Gould with William Wright, her brother, for years 1851, 1852, 1853, 1857, 1858, 1860, 1861; Deed of burying ground lot for Hannah W. Gould, May 23, 1908; Handwritten codicil to Hannah W. Gould's will plus 4 half sheets of Benoni Johnson letterhead containing "Instructions as to Probate of Hannah Wright Gould's Will" and one half sheet of plain paper containing a form for an affadavit; Copy of Hannah W. Gould's will with an attached halfsheet from the "Clerk to the Surrogate's Court," Sept. 13, 1912 - declaring it to be a true copy
  - Legal Documents, Hannah Wright Gould (continued), 1886-1913 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Copy of last will and testament of Hannah W. Gould, Nov. 30, 1886, with sheet attached signed by the Surrogate - a Letters Testamentary declaring Benoni S. Johnson executor of H. W. G.'s will, July 8, 1912; Inventory of the estate, Nov. 4, 1912; receipt from Hannah Gould Johnson Stoddard, Nov. 20, 1912; Receipt from Elizabeth W. Berry, April 22, 1913; Receipt from Rebekah W. Smith, April 22, 1913; Sheet of letterhead of Romeyn Berry, Feb. 1, 1913, receipt of payment for professional services - signed Romeyn Berry; Form dealing with publishing of Notice to Creditors on H. W. Gould's will, clipping posed to form is dated Oct. 18, 1912; Letter from Hannah W. Gould, June 24, 1903, to Benoni S. Johnson concerning her will
  - Legal Documents, John Stanton Gould, 1854-1915 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Deed for farm sold to J. A. Van Valkenburgh by John Stanton Gould; Bond, Jeremiah Bundell to John Stanton Gould Special Guardian (Guardian of Lord Ashby Gould, Mary Wanton Gould and William Ashby Gould, infants), October 22, 1855; Gilbert Everson to John Stanton Gould (Mr. Everson had some land in New York City and turned over negotiations with the city to J. S. G.), Jan. 7, 1861; Statement of contents of box at Farmers National Bank belonging to the estate of John S. Gould, 1905; Inventory of the Estate of John S. Gould, July 1, 1907; Certificate of indebtedness Hudson City Cemetery re upkeep of cemetery plot, signed by Louis H. Payne, Michael Baier, and Henry M. James, May 29, 1914
  - Legal Documents, John Stanton Gould, Marshall Estate Papers, 1848-1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Papers relating to John Stanton Gould's work as Administrator of the estate of Joseph Marshall (John Stanton Gould was nephew by marriage to Benjamin Marshall - Joseph's brother. John had worked as a chemist in the Marshall brothers' calico printworks - information taken from "The Town of Stockport Items Collected for the Daughters of Columbia County Historical Society"); Receipts for burial expenses, Sept 23 1848, Nov 22, 1851; Thomas Marshall (nephew to Joseph) formerly of Stockport but at that time living in Almondbury, York, England relinquishes claim in payment of one dollar to him, Jan. 14, 1849; Katherine Gough to J. S. Gould - release Feb. 27, 1849 (June 1, 1853, Van Alen & Co. received $100, 10% of the claim allowed to Catherine Gough); Series of receipts for money received from the estate of J. Marshall on account on a note - paid to John Kearsley and later to his widow Ann Kearsley, March 6, 1849-Oct. 17, 1869; Series of receipts on account on a note paid to Ann Pilling per Mary Pilling (and other members of the Pilling family), March 26, 1849-Nov. 1, 1860; Samuel Marshall received one dollar for claim against the estate, July 12, 1849; Samuel Marshall built a vault, July 12, 1849; Samuel Marshall receipted bill for bricks, etc., July 12, 1849; A number of receipted bills for the estate - many had been settled for 10% - dated from Feb 29, 1848-Jan 4, 1861; Items dealing with auctions of goods and expenses attendant upon the auction (printer's bill, auctioneer, etc.)
  - Legal Documents, John Stanton Gould, Marshall Estate Papers (continued, 1848-1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Bills, receipts, etc. relating to legal services connected with appraising the estate, probating the will, etc., Sept 23, 1848-July 19, 1860; A. A. Van Alen & Co. litigation against the estate; Three sheets dealing with rents due on land to John Van Der Car by Joseph Marshall, June 23, 1860
  - Legal Documents, John Stanton Gould, Guardianship and Trustee Papers, 1855-1871 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    John Gifford received of John S. Gould $4,310 "... .being the full amount due me as my guardian"; Bills from Saul and Esselstyn (lawyers?); Documents dealing with business between Elizabeth Robinson and Frederick Farraud in regards to some property, Oct 1, 1862; (Foreclosure) Supreme Court - J. S. Gould Trustee for Elizabeth Robinson, wife of George Robinson against George Robinson et al, Aug. 25, 1863; Papers relating to guardianship of Mary E. Van Steenburgh: letter of guardianship, December 1867; record of income (1 sheet), 1868-1871; receipts for yearly amounts paid to Eliza Paul for the maintenance, support and education of Miss Van Steenburgh, 1868-1870
  - Legal Documents, John Stanton Gould, Coventry and Reynold Papers, 1836-1867 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Rental agreement between John Stanton Gould and George Coventry, Feb. 20, 1836; 1 inventory and appraisement of goods to remain in the possession of Catherine Coventry, widow of the testator; April 1852 copy of the will in Surrogate Court, will made Feb. 14, 1842, Codicil, Feb. 17, 1852, will proved April 28, 1852
  - Legal Documents, John Stanton Gould, Coventry and Reynold Papers (continued), 1836-1867 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Receipt by H. W. Reynolds for bond No, 26550 dated March 1864, $1000 deposited with John Stanton Gould, June 6, 1867; Will of Henry W. Reynolds, Sept. 24, 2867; Certificate from Surrogate Court proving will, Sept. 26, 1867
  - Legal Documents, Miscellaneous, 1847-1906 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Warranty deed, Henry Brown and wife to Robert G. Frary (land deal), Jan. 29, 1847; Promissory note: Solomon B. Veil promises to pay Theophilus Pegler $150 plus interest, back of slip receipted, May 15, 1848; Francis Silvester, report new deed for $94,744.35, Mar. 17, 1851; Bill to G. D. Smith for mahogany coffin, Nov. 22, 1851; Demand note (for Jn. 1858) by Azubah and Cornelius Van Valkenburgh to Barent Van Alstyne, Apr. 11, 1857; Second note for June 1, 1867; Recorded Nov. 21, 1865, executors deed - Henry I. Whiting and Ira S. Johnson, executors of Robert G. Frary, Apr. 17, 1865; "Contents of box at Farmer's National Bank Belonging to Sarah A. Gould," 1905; Copy of will of Elizabeth Wright, Jan. 15, 1875; Codicil, Dec. 4, 1879; Assignment of mortgage, Orrin H. Walker to F. Finch witnessed by H. S. Johnson, Apr. 20, 1908
- Series VI. Photographs
  - Photograph (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Mr. Gould
  - Stereopticon Slide (Box 16, Folder 1)
    John Stanton Gould's Birthplace, Newport
  - Photographs (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Goodwin Stoddard, 2 portraits
  - Photographs (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Hannah G. Johnson (infant); Annie W. G. Johnson (mother), in leather case
  - Photographic Image (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Group of people at Niagara Falls, in black leather case
  - Photograph (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Henry Sisson
  - Photograph (Box 16, Folder 7)
    G. [Clason?]
  - Photograph (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Capt. H. L. Parker
  - Photograph (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Gertrude (Peggy?) DuBois Campbell (friend of Hannah G. Johnson Stoddard from Hudson, N.Y.)
  - Photograph (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Sanford Stoddard
  - Photograph, 1880 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    "Babety" Stoddard, 9/15/1880, probably Sanford Stoddard ( b.1880)
  - Photographs (Box 16, Folder 12)
    Julia Sanford Stoddard, 2 portraits
  - Photograph (Box 16, Folder 13)
    Julia Sanford Stoddard, wife of Goodwin Stoddard
  - Photograph (Box 16, Folder 14)
    Edwin G. Sanford (right), father of Julia Sanford Stoddard
  - Photograph, 1896 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    Goodwin Stoddard (1847-1909)
  - Photograph (Box 16, Folder 16)
    Geo A. Greene, Ashville, Chautauqua Co., NY "Republican"
  - Photograph (Box 16, Folder 17)
    Mabel Judson Sanford Jennings (1873-1910)
  - Photographs (Box 16, Folder 18)
    Goodwin Stoddard (1847-1909), 3 portraits
  - Photographs (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Photographs, 1896, 1904 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    6 women posing, 1896; young woman, 1904
  - Photographs, 1901 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Mary Belle & May Barrett (sp?), Smith (graduation?)
  - Photographs, 1901 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Hannah G. Johnson
  - Photographs, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Sanford and Hannah Stoddard, driving on York Beach, Sept. 1910
  - Photographs, 1910(?) (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Round Robin Letters, snapshots
  - Photographs, 1913, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Mary B. Lewis, family snapshots (one of the White Lodge Round Robin Letters participants)
  - Photographs, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Goodwin Stoddard (Sanford & Hannah's son)
  - Photographs, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Gould Mansion & D.A.R. House in 1920, one unidentified photograph
  - Photographs, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    David Gould Stoddard, b. 1912 (Sanford & Hannah's son)
  - Photographic Negatives, 1922, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Canaan Houseparty, 1922; Lake Placid, 1923, Lake Placid - Hart Lake
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Unidentified people and cars
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Unidentified people
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 13)
    Back yard and European scenes
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 14)
    Northern Africa
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Italian and Dutch scenes
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 16)
    Two unidentified young children
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Outdoor snapshots
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Western U.S.A.
  - Photographs - unidentified (Box 17, Folder 20-21)
  - Photographs - trip to Europe? (Box 17, Folder 22-23)
  - Photographs - Western U.S.A., Native Americans and Native American structures (Box 17, Folder 24-27)
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 28)
    Western U.S.A., magazine photos of Grand Canyon
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 29)
    Photo greeting to the Sanford Stoddards from Des Moines, from "Agnes and Wads"
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 30)
    Gov. & Mrs. Joseph Wanton (copies of paintings)
  - Photograph (Box 17, Folder 31)
    Lake Placid in winter
  - Photograph (Box 17, Folder 32)
    Sanford & Hannah G. J. Stoddard
  - Photograph (Box 17, Folder 33)
    Jefferson, N. H., The Waumbek (sp?)
  - Photograph (Box 17, Folder 34)
    David Gould Stoddard, b. 1912, (Sanford & Hannah's third son)
- Series VII. Microfilm
  Note: Negative microfilm of 12 volumes of S. W. G. diaries held by the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections and 1 volume of Quaker monthly meeting records, filmed by Photo Services, Feb. 2, 1966. Reel 2 contains positive microfilm of Volume 11 only, purchased from Haverford College, Feb. 2, 1966. Positive microfilm of the 14 volumes held by this Division made by Photo Services from our negatives July 6, 1973, January 26, 1978.
  - Diary #1, 1799-1803 (Reel 1)
    Nov. 1799-Oct. 16, 1803 (1 reel pos.)